



Matteo Simoni

Date of birth: 29/11/1994 **\Cong Phone:** (+39) 3336751098

Email: simonimatteo29@gmail.com

in LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/simoni-matteo
• Home: Via Cutigliano 65, 00146 Roma (Italy)

ABOUT MYSELF

I am a **trained professional** with solid experience as an IT developer and consultant, as well as an **passionate gamer**. My ambition is to **create innovative games** and **experiment with new ideas**, bringing creativity and technical expertise to every project.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Game Programming Course Trainer

Red Hog Studio [06/2024 - 12/2024]

City: Roma | Country: Italy | Business/sector: Education

Master Online (Digital Bros):

Teaching two modules: *Unreal Engine Basics* (key concepts and fundamentals of the engine) e *C++ Programming* (C++ programming for advanced game development).

(November 2024 - December 2024)

Digital Game Specialist (ITS Rossellini):

Lessons dedicated to programming fundamentals in C++ and introduction to the use of Unreal Engine for video game development.

(October 2024 - November 2024)

• Blended Online (Digital Bros):

Conducted a course in English on C++ programming fundamentals and introduction to development on Unreal Engine. The program covered basic and advanced concepts, including artificial intelligence. Responsible for the planning and management of the entire course. (June 2024 – November 2024)

Game Developer Intern

Red Hog Studio [12/2023 - 05/2024]

City: Roma | Country: Italy

Description:

720-hour internship focused on the development of an endless runner video game using Unreal Engine 5. **Responsibilities:**

- Programming in C++ to develop the game from scratch.
- Using Unreal Engine 5 blueprints to implement game mechanics.
- Research and implementation of innovative solutions for basic and advanced game mechanics.
- Implementation of features for saving scores and managing design variables, such as object sizes and Actor spawn probabilities.
- Configuring the engine for mobile build, preparing the build for Android using Android Studio.

Technologies and Tools Used:

· Languages: C++

• Engine: Unreal Engine 5

• IDE: Riders from JetBrains

Fullstack Developer

SiliconDev s.p.a. [05/2022 – 11/2022]

City: Roma | Country: Italy

Description:

Member of a development team responsible for applications and systems used by Fideuram - Intesa Sanpaolo Private Banking S.p.A. in customer, confidential and commercial areas.

Responsibilities:

- Learning and working with new languages and technologies, including PHP, Ext JS, Jspx and Java batch creation and scheduling.
- Follow specific procedures for testing and releases, including operations such as remote access to service machines and manual deployment of applications.
- Full-stack development with SQL or host relational databases for the backend (Java with Spring or Spring Boot) and PHP, JavaScript, JSP for the frontend.
- Use of Linux Command Prompt, WinSCP and FTP for system operations and deployments.

Technologies and Tools Used:

- Backend: Java, Spring, Spring Boot
- Frontend: PHP, JavaScript, JSP, Ext JS
- Version Control Tools: Jazz Source Repository

Software Developer and Tester b/e

Engineering [02/2022 - 04/2022]

City: Roma | Country: Italy

Description:

I work in a maintenance team for the Lombardy Region Document Platform (EDMA), managing internal and external documents for administrative activities.

Responsibilities:

- Resolving bugs reported through a ticket system.
- Analyzing use cases, modifying or adding Java code and SQL scripts to resolve errors.
- Local testing of modified use cases to verify the effectiveness of the solution.
- Use of SVN (TortoiseSVN client) for version control and commit of modified code.

Technologies and Tools Used:

- Languages: Java, SQL
- Version Control Tools: SVN (TortoiseSVN)

Software Developer and Analyst

Aubay [08/2021 - 01/2022]

City: Roma | Country: Italy

Description:

Development and completion of two applications for an integrated system for TIM, focused on credit planning and revenue reporting.

Responsibilities:

- Correction and development of SQL procedure stores and Java/Spring Data JPA methods for interfacing with relational databases.
- Build and deploy applications in Docker containers with flat jars generated via Maven and deploy to Microsoft Azure.
- Creation of health check scripts to monitor containers in cloud environment.
- Backend development in Spring Boot for conversion automation and document generation.
- Front-end component development in Angular and testing of back-end services with Postman.

Technologies and Tools Used:

- Languages: Java, SQL
- Framework: Spring Boot, Spring Data JPA, Angular
- Container: DockerCloud: Microsoft Azure
- Build e Deployment Tools: Maven
- **Testing:** Postman
- IDE: VSCode

Software Developer and Tester

Ericsson [04/2021 - 08/2021]

City: Roma | Country: Italy

Description:

Participation in the development and testing of projects to manage WIND's surcharge, subscription and charging services.

Responsibilities:

- Management of new phone lines with development of Java code and REST services for CRUD on Oracle database.
- Use of Activiti for collaborative workflow management and creation.

Technologies and Tools Used:

- Languages: JavaDatabase: Oracle
- Build e Deployment Tools: Maven, Ant, Jenkins, Git
- **IDE**: Eclipse
- Testing: Postman
- Server: Oracle WebLogic su Oracle VM VirtualBox

Software Developer Junior

Web For Enterprise s.r.l. [04/2020 – 03/2021]

City: Roma | Country: Italy

Description:

Development of an application for managing the technological skills of company employees, integrated into the company intranet.

Responsibilities:

- Development of Angular forms for self-assessment of technology skills by registered employees.
- Implementation of functionality for HR staff to view and search employee competencies.
- Admin HR can add new technologies for self-assessments, while users with User privileges can only view and search skills.

Technologies and Tools Used:

- Front End: HTML5, Bootstrap/CSS, TypeScript, Angular 8
- Back End: Spring Boot, Spring Restful (API Swagger/Hateoas), Spring Data JPA, Hibernate
- Database: H2 (test e sviluppo), MySQL, MongoDB
- Runtime Environment: Tomcat
- Building Tool: Maven
- · Versioning: Git
- Microservizi: Spring Cloud (API Gateway, Eureka, Zipkin, Sleuth), Docker (orchestration with Docker-Swarm)

Features Implemented:

- HR user registration and access
- Employee profile management
- Technology skills entry and categorization
- Self-evaluation of competencies
- · Viewing skills by employee

Technological Approach:

- From monolith (Angular and Spring Boot) to cloud-native microservices
- Using Spring Cloud (Eureka Server, Config Server, API Gateway) and Keycloak for Oauth 2

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Higher Technician Degree in Game Development

ITS Academy "LazioDigital"

City: Roma | Country: Italy | Website: https://www.laziodigital.it/ | Final grade: 100/100 con lode | Level in

EQF: EQF level 5

Moduli affrontati:

Fondamenti di game development -Programmazione C++ con Unreal -Programmazione C# con Unity -Programmazione di Shader -La pipeline 3D -Metaverso AR VR -Metodologie di Analisi e Progettazione del Software (UML) -Metodologie di Project Management -Informatica di base -Fondamenti di Agile -Sicurezza sul lavoro -Matematica e Statistica - Inglese tecnico -Diritto informatico

Project Works:

- Pipeline 3D
- Unity Game
- Unreal Game
- Shader

Microservice application development course in cloud architecture

Web For Enterprise S.r.l.

City: Roma | Country: Italy | Website: https://www.web4enterprise.it/

Angular course

Web For Enterprise S.r.l.

City: Roma | Country: Italy | Website: https://www.web4enterprise.it/

angular bootstrap, input and output components, pipe, directive, forms, ciclo di vita, eventi, typescript, angular material, moduli core, shared, feature strutturazione di un'applicazione, dependency injection, servizi, restful call

Generation "JAVA AND JAVA EE DEVELOPER" course - Generation Italy, at ELIS Center

Elis Corporate School

City: Roma | Country: Italy | Website: https://www.elis.org/

Scientific High School Diploma

Liceo Scientifico Giovanni Keplero

City: Roma | Country: Italy | Website: https://www.liceokepleroroma.edu.it/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 4

DIGITAL SKILLS

Game Development

Unreal Engine 5 / Video Game Development With Unity - C# Object Oriented Programming. / Programming in C++ and Blueprint in Unreal Engine / Blender / Autodesk Maya / Shader Programming

Software Development

Git, GitHub, Versioning Control Systems / Docker, Jenkins, Openshift, Kubernetes, progettazione architetture a Microservizi / Spring framework (Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Spring Data, Spring Security, Spring Batch) / Java / Good knowledge of Angular / MySQL and Database Skills / Non-relational databases (MongoDB)

HONOURS AND AWARDS

[07/2023] Ministry of Education and Merit

Second place in the "Servizi Digitali" ("Digital Services") category - ITS 4.0 2023:

ITS 4.0 event in 2023 with the video game Games Bond

Links: https://www.laziodigital.it/contest-its-4-0-secondo-posto-per-lits-lazio-digital/ | https://www.behance.net/gallery/199297823/Games-Bond

CERTIFICATIONS AND CERTIFICATES

Oracle Certification "Java SE8 Fundamentals"

Course certificate "Sviluppo di applicazioni a microservizi in architettura cloud" ("Development of microservice applications in cloud architecture")

"Sviluppatore Java Junior" ("Junior Java Developer") course certificate

EIPASS 7 User Modules

Certificate for Workers - Low Risk

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Italiano

Other language(s):

Inglese

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: B

Matteo Simoni

Grami Matter